right.
Okay,
let's rub it out.
So keeping your friends under control Some of you may guess where this is already going,
but so imagine you have a class fare
class badger,
of course.
Why not Onda pastor members,
The creator instance of this class Badger notice.
It's in this name.
Space animals.
Of course you can.
You can call this free function that operates on on Bajor,
just as it is because we have arguments,
spending.
Look up.
So that's the polices.
So I haven't looked at this for a little while.
Of course,
you can also qualify that free function with the name space that is in and now works as
well.
Then we're not using,
but interestingly,
if you put that free function inside the class as a friend
on also make it in line.
This is now no longer findable using idea because it's technically not
in that enclosing name space,
which means the only way Sorry.
The only way to find it is with a D l.
Let's get that the wrong way around.
So if you try to call it qualified of name space,
that's an error.
But if you call it unqualified ideal picks it up,
so I can't remember.
Why put this light in.
I know this is a bad idea,
but anyway,
what's the what's the benefit of this?
Is it just a curiosity?
Well,
imagine we're talking about operators.
The Austrian operator overload here.
Now we introduce another class that Z not in that name space.
If we introduce an era,
this is a sort of error message we're going to see.
I'm sure you're familiar with this.
In fact,
this is just an extract and hopefully you can read it all.
But in case you can't zoom in,
there's a bit that actually reflects the area that we introduced the rest of it's just
noise coming from all the additional overloads that we're finding because of a d.
R.
So if we can hide all of these overloads from medial,
then we can drastically reduce the number of areas that we got,
and that sort of reflects the what we cut out.
But I'll zoom straight
onto this.
This proposal from Watery Brown and others recommendations
for specifying hidden friends So this was actually raised is
a standard proposal for the benefit off other standards proposals so that they
can consider using this technique to reduce the number of overloads that we
we actually exposed to,
not just error messages but also compel times as well.
Having to consider all those additional overloads has a bit of a drag.
So I think really good they were going in the direction.
Whether you actually use this technique yourself is up to you because there is a
trade off in that you do have to make them in line Friends of the
class,
which may not have bean what you wanted to do.
Otherwise,
there is another proposal,
the Independence of Declaration,
which proposes a new key word to actually allow you to do the same thing without
changing how you design the code.
But do note the date of this proposal.
Mhm,
April the first thing this year.
I'm not saying that means anything,
but if you wanna go and have a look at that,
they get hobbling.
So that was it.
Thank you.